Kiwan Maeng

CONTACT Information CIC 4th floor Carnegie Mellon University

4720 Forbes Avenue Pittsburgh, PA 15213

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interest lies in co-designing a programming model, a compiler and a runtime system for emerging platforms. Current research focuses on co-designing of hardwares, compilers, and runtime systems for energy-harvesting IoT devices.

Research Area: Computer System, Compiler, IoT, Embedded System, Intermittent Computing, Energy-Harvesting Device

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Aug 2016 -

Homepage: https://kiwanmaeng.com

Email: kmaeng@andrew.cmu.edu

Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

- Advisor: Prof. Brandon Lucia

Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering Graduated with Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 4.14/4.30) Aug 2016

Referred Papers

- [1] Supporting Peripherals in Intermittent Systems with Just-In-Time Checkpoints <u>Kiwan Maeng</u> and Brandon Lucia **PLDI 2019** Programming Language Design and Implementation
- [2] Adaptive Dynamic Checkpointing for Safe Efficient Intermittent Computing
 <u>Kiwan Maeng</u> and Brandon Lucia

 OSDI 2018 USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation
- [3] Alpaca: Intermittent Execution without Checkpoints <u>Kiwan Maeng</u>, Alexei Colin and Brandon Lucia **OOPSLA 2017** - Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages & Applications
- [4] Intermittent Computing: Challenges and Opportunities Brandon Lucia, Vignesh Balaji, Alexei Colin, <u>Kiwan Maeng</u>, and Emily Ruppel SNAPL 2017

OTHER PAPERS

[5] Enhancing Stratospheric Weather Analysis and Forecasts by Deploying Sensors from a Weather Balloon

Kiwan Maeng, Iskender Kushan, Brandon Lucia and Ashish Kapoor NeurIPS 2019 Climate Change Workshop (spotlight talk)

[6] Getting Started with Intermittent Computing Brandon Lucia, Emily Ruppel, <u>Kiwan Maeng</u>, Graham Gobieski and Milijana Surbatovich

MICRO 2018 Tutorial

[7] The Midnight Engineers (Book, Korean)

Kiwan Maeng

Science comicbook for non-majors (LINK).

Won several awards including 10 Authors of the Year 2017.

A١	VARDS
&	HONORS

Korea Foundation for Advanced Studies Scholarship, KFAS2016 – 2021Summa Cum Laude, Seoul National UniversityAug 2016National Scholarship for Science & Engineering, KOSAF2010 – 2016

Work Experience

Microsoft Research, Bellevue, WA

May 2019 – Aug 2019

Research Intern with Ashish Kapoor

• Tasks: Developing hardware and software systems for sensor devices that collect stratospheric weather data and relay the data to ground [5].

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Sep 2016 -

Research Assistant with Prof. Brandon Lucia

- Tasks: Developing hardware and software systems for energy-harvesting devices. Recent work include designing compilers, programming models, and a HW/SW runtime system for energy-harvesting devices [1-3].
- Skills: C, C++, LLVM (backend), Clang (frontend), Python, TI MSP430, GNU make

Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

March 2015 - Aug 2016

Research Intern with Prof. Hyuk-Jae Lee

- Tasks: Developed hardware for computer vision.
- Skills: Verilog, C, FPGA

Rsupport Inc., Seoul, Korea

Feb 2013 - Dec 2015

QA Engineer

- Tasks: Developed internal test automation framework.
- Skills: Java, Selenium

GRADUATE
Coursework

18-748 Wireless Sensor Networks	Spring 2018
18-643 Reconfigurable Logic: Technology, Architecture and Applications	Fall 2017
18-797 Machine Learning for Signal Processing	Fall 2017
15-745 Optimizing Compilers for Modern Architectures	Spring 2017
18-742 Advanced Computer Architecture and Systems	Spring 2017
14-642 Introduction to Embedded Systems	Fall 2016
18-743 Energy Aware Computing	Fall 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- C (Advanced) / C++, Python (Experienced) / Verilog, Java, Swift (Intermediate)
- Developing compilers using Clang (frontend) and LLVM (backend).
- Designing embedded systems, mainly using TI MSP430 microprocessor.

References

Available on request